Finding aid to the Individual Faculty records CA.MS.01008
Smith College Archives
Individual Faculty papers
1875-2018
Smith College Archives
Smith College--Faculty.
CA.MS.01008
77.75 linear feet (179 containers)
Faculty files contain the personal and professional papers of individual faculty members.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation. Faculty tenure and promotion files, as well as inactive faculty files are closed permanently. Student academic records, student disciplinary records, and all records containing FERPA-covered student information are closed during the lifetime of the student. Student records created 100 years or more ago are assumed to be about deceased students. In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Unknown source
Scope and Contents
Files are arranged alphabetically. Material may include photographs, news clippings, biographical material. Some include personal papers: class notes, publications, research notes, correspondence, journals, etc.
Smith College--Faculty
- A-Alde (Box 654)
- Jere Abbott (Box 659)
- Albertson-An (Box 654.1)
- Gladys Amelia Anslow (Box 664)
- Dorothy May Anderson (Box 663)
- App-Az (Box 655)
- Adrienne Auerswald scrapbooks and photo album (Box 665.1)
- B-Barl (Box 666)
- Barn-Bart (Box 667)
- Leonard Baskin (Box 668)
- Bat-Bax (Box 669)
- Be (Box 670)
- Bh-Bi (Box 671)
- Bl-Bli (Box 671.1)
- Blo-Bor (Box 672)
- Benjamin C. Blodgett: Scores (Box 2)
- Boss-Brain (Box 673)
- Bram-Bry (Box 673.1)
- Bu-Burnett, Edith (Box 674)
- Burnett-Bz (Box 674.1)
- C-Can (Box 693)
- Cap-Carp (Box 693.1)
- Carr-Chan (Box 693.2)
- Chap-Chit (Box 693.3)
- Chm-Clark (Box 693.4)
- Clarke-Colville (Box 693.5)
- Com-Cra (Box 693.6)
- Mary Merrow Cook (Box 730, Folder 5-9)
- Cre-Cz (Box 694)
- D-Daw (Box 742)
- Day-Den (Box 742.1)
- Dep-Die (Box 742.2)
- Dig-Driver (Box 742.3)
- Driver-Dz (Box 742.4)
- E-Elliot (Box 781)
- Ellis-Ez (Box 782)
- Alvin D. Etler (Box 784)
- Alvin D. Etler: "Making Music" proofs (Box 785.3)
- Alvin D. Etler: Manuscript "Passacoglia and Fugue" (Box 785.1)
- Alvin D. Etler: Publications (Box 785.2)
- Alvin D. Etler: Publications and recordings (Box 785)
- Fa-Fe (Box 786)
- Fi (Box 787)
- Fl-Fo (Box 788)
- Fr-Fz (Box 789)
- G-Gan (Box 804)
- Gao-Geo (Box 805)
- Charles E. Garman and Eliza N. Garman (Box 825.1)
- Ger-Gib (Box 806)
- Gif-Gl (Box 826.1)
- Gn-Go (Box 826.2)
- Gra-Gre (Box 830)
- William Dodge Gray (Box 832.1)
- William Dodge Gray: A-Publications (Box 831.1)
- William Dodge Gray: Publications (Box 832)
- Grierson-Gu (Box 835)
- Hackett-Hammons (Box 836)
- Hanfmann-Harvie (Box 836.1)
- Elizabeth Deering Hanscom (Box 850)
- Harward-Hefferman (Box 837.1)
- Emma Hawks (Class of 1892) journals, 1887-1961 (Box 3, Box 4)
- Heldman-Hill, B. (Box 838)
- Hill-Holl (Box 839)
- Vera Brown Holmes (Box 879)
- Hom-Hub (Box 839.1)
- Mary Murray Hopkins (Box 870)
- Elizabeth B. Horner (Box 871)
- Elizabeth Horner (Box 871.1)
- Hunt-Hz (Box 840)
- I (Box 875)
- Ja-Je (Box 875.1)
- Mary Lois James memorabilia book (Box 877)
- Jo-Joh (Box 876)
- Jon (Box 878)
- Jop-Jz (Box 878.1)
- Werner Josten: "Ode to St. Cecilia's Day" music manuscript (Box 8)
- Ka-Kennedy (Box 883)
- Margaret Kemp (Box 886, Box 887)
- Margaret Kemp: Photo albums and botanical drawing (Box 887.1)
- Kennedy-Kind (Box 884)
- King-Kio (Box 890)
- Kir-Kof (Box 891)
- Helen Paull Kirkpatrick (Class of 1931; Assistant to the President, 1953-1955) (Box 891.1)
- Koh-Kz (Box 892)
- L-Lane (Box 893)
- Lange-Leh (Box 894)
- Lei-Lock (Box 909)
- Joan Hatch Lennox (Box 925)
- Eleanor Terry Lincoln: A-Pub (Box 927)
- Eleanor Terry Lincoln: Pub-Z (Box 928)
- Thomas Litwin (Box 928.1)
- Arthur Ware Locke (Box 929, Box 929.1)
- Lod-Ly (Box 930)
- Eleanor Louisa Lord (1887) (Box 931)
- M-McCoy (Box 934)
- MacCracken-MacSherry (Box 936)
- William L. MacDonald (Box 942)
- Maci-Mar (Box 937)
- Ernst Heinrich Mensel: Three volume edition of Goethe's Faust (Box 944)
- Mas-Mey (Box 938)
- Howard Meyerhoff (Geology, 1924-1950) (Box 945)
- Mi (Box 939)
- Roger Miller (Box 946)
- Mo (Box 940)
- Mu-My (Box 941)
- N (Box 950)
- O (Box 959.1)
- Elizabeth Warren Olmsted (1931): A-Z (Box 960)
- P-Par (Box 961)
- Pas-Pei (Box 964)
- Howard Rollin Patch: A-Z (Box 965)
- Howard Rollin Patch: Publications (Box 966)
- Ludella Peck (Box 1)
- Pel-Pn (Box 967)
- Margaret Hill Peoples Photo Album, 1916-1940 (Box 969)
- Po-Pr (Box 982)
- Grace Alma Preston (1888) (Box 977)
- Pu-Q (Box 983)
- R-Rice (Box 984)
- Helen Rees (Box 985)
- Rich-Riv (Box 986)
- Ro-Robe (Box 987)
- Robi-Robs (Box 988)
- Roc-Roo (Box 989)
- Rop-Roz (Box 992)
- Stanley Curtis Ross (Economics, 1944-1961) (Box 992.1, Box 992.2)
- Stanley Rothman (Box 993)
- Ru-Rz (Box 994)
- Helen Russell (Box 993.1)
- Sa (Box 995)
- Sca-Sch (Box 995.1)
- Marshall Schalk (Box 1011.1)
- Sco-Sec (Box 995.2)
- K. Frances Scott (Box 1014)
- Sed-Sha (Box 995.3)
- She-Sis (Box 995.4)
- Elsa Siipola (Box 1017)
- Doris Silbert (Box 1018)
- Doris Silbert: Music for "An Evening of Renaissance Music", 1953-10-30 (Box 1018.1)
- Sk-Sn (Box 995.5)
- Henry Dike Sleeper: Scores (Box 5)
- Gertrude Parker Smith (1928) (Box 1023, Box 1023.3)
- Florence Homer Snow (Box 1021)
- So-Steg (Box 995.6)
- Stei-Sz (Box 995.7)
- Ninian Stein (visiting faculty, 2013-): ENV201/202 oral histories (Box 1025.1)
- T-Te (Box 1030)
- William Sentam Taylor (1921-2009) (Box 1031.1, Box 1032, Box 1033, Box 1034)
- Phoebe Taylor (Mrs. William Sentam Taylor) (Box 1035)
- Th (Box 1030.1)
- Ti-Tu (Box 1031)
- Ty-Tz (Box 1038)
- U-Ve (Box 1039)
- Vi-Wak (Box 1040)
- Fran Volkmann: Research on coeducation, 1990s (Box 1040.1)
- Klemens von Klemperer (Box 1040.2)
- Wal-Watk (Box 1041)
- Julia Warner (Box 1043)
- Wats-Wes (Box 1044)
- Essie Watson scrapbook (Box 6)
- Leon Weinstein (Box 1045)
- Wh-Will (Box 1046)
- Robert Withington: General (Box 1087)
- Robert Withington: Publications (Box 1088)
- Robert Withington: Publications -- English pageantry (Box 1089)
- Robert Withington: Marginalia in century, readings in English literature, etc. (Box 1090)
- Wils-Woodhouse (Box 1091)
- Irving F. Wood (Box 1092.1)
- Woodman-Y (Box 1092)
- Kate Shepard Woodward memorabilia book (Box 7)
- Z (Box 1093)